Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Community Service Society Archives,
1842-1995.
Community Service Society.
280 linear ft. (616 boxes; 123 bound volumes; 9 packages; 1 crate; 4 framed items (shelved at end of original collection and end of series II).
The Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, 6th floor, Columbia University, 535 West 114th Street, New York, N.Y., 10027.
4079675
History
The Community Service Society, a large, private, New York City social service agency. The society was established in 1939 from a merger of the Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor and the Charity Organization Society, whose separate files make up most of the collection.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, case records, photographs and printed material. The archive include central and district administrative records; cammittee correspondence and minutes; and files on the various programs--such as sheltered workshops, tuberculosis sanitariums and health centers, public baths and employment bureaus--run by the two organizations. The archive also contains hundreds of photographs, including works by Lewis Hine and Jessie Tarbox Beals; extensive casework files from the beginning of social work (originally referred to as "friendly visiting among the poor"); and copies of masters and doctoral theses from the New York School of Sociel Work and other schools. Much of the research for these theses was based on the CSS files.
Among the major correspondence are: Jane Addams; Cornelius N. Bliss; Robert W. DeForest; Edward T. Devine; Irving Fisher; Homer Folks; Harry L. Hopkins; Florence Kelley; Paul U. Kellogg; Fiorello La Guardia; Josephine Shaw Lowell; Frances Perkins; Lawson Purdy; Jacob Riis; Beardsley Ruml; Alfred E. Smith; Lawrence Veiller; Lilliam Wald; and Alfred T. White.
Series XIV continues the files from the time of the merger in 1939 until 1960, and contains the same types of materials as the original gift; similarly, Series XV covers primarily the period from 1960-1970. Series XVI contains the additions to the files for the years 1970-1984, but there are also files for the period ca.1935-1969. Series XVII contains additions primarily for the period 1970-1986, but also contains some files for ca.1945-1969. Series XVIII contains legal and financial additions primarily for the period 1970 & following, and the files of H. Dogue.
Arrangement
Series I: Catalogued Correspondence
Series II: Catalogued Manuscripts & Documents
Series III: Catalogued Photographs
Series IV: Association For Improving The Condition Of The Poor
Series V: Charity Organization Society
Series VI: CSS Press Releases, 1944-1970 and Scrapbook
Series VII: Masters Theses
Series VIII: Casework Files
Series IX: Photographs
Series X: Printed Materials
Series XI: Memorabilia and Miscellaneous Items
Series XII: Bound Volumes
Series XIII: Oversize
Series XIV: Files, 1939-1960
Series XV: Reports, Pamphlets, Pictures
Series XVI: Historical Data, 1970 & Following
Series XVII: Files, 1970-1986
Series XVIII: Legal and Financial Matters, and H. Dogue Materials
Subjects
New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor.; Charity Organization Society.; Addams, Jane, 1860-1935.; Beals, Jessie Tarbox.; Bliss, Cornelius Newton, 1833-1911.; De Forest, Robert W. (Robert Weeks), 1848-1931.; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947.; Hine, Lewis Wickes, 1874-1940.; Hopkins, Harry L. (Harry Lloyd), 1890-1946.; Kelly, Florence, 1859-1932.; Kellogg, Paul Underwood, 1879-1958.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965.; Riis, Jacob A. (Jacob August), 1849-1914.; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944.; Veiller, Lawrence, 1872-1959.; Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940.; White, Alfred Tredway, 1846-1921.; New York (N.Y.); Education.; Health.; Public health.; Social problems.; Public welfare.; Annual reports.; Case files.; Indexes.; Ledgers.; Minutes.; Reports.; Photographs.; Theses.; Child welfare workers.; Photographers.; Social workers.; Women photographers.; Women social workers.
Access Restrictions
Available for faculty, students, and researchers engaged in scholarly or publication projects.
Box 424; General Director, Evaluation of His Performance (box 489); "Joey" Admission Records (box 494); Supplemental Security Income (box 509); Trustees, Study Data (box 541); and Special Administration Committee Meeting, Dec. 1951 (box 549) are closed.
Readers must sign a special agreement form, kept in a folder at the Reference Center.
Acquisition
1979 M-1979-1988 Community Service Society Gift, 1979-1988
12/04/1996 M-96-12-04 8 annual reports CSS Gift
Alternate Formats
Josephine Shaw Lowell letters; Interview book (Box 180); and Handbook for friendly visitors (Box 182); Index of New Cases, 1906-1908 (leger book) are on microfilm.
Gift of the Society, 1979, 1981, 1986, & 1988.
- Series I: Catalogued Correspondence
  - Addams, Jane (Box 1)
  - Aspinwall, William H. (Box 1)
  - Astor, Ava Lowle Willing (Mrs. John Jacob) (Box 1)
  - Astor, John Macob (1822-1890 ) (Box 1)
  - Auchincloss, Hugh D. (Box 1)
  - Audubon, M.(Maria) R.(Rebecca) (Box 1)
  - Aydelotte, Frank (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, William Henry (1851-1923 ) (Box 1)
  - Barnum, Phineas Taylor (1810-1891 ) (Box 1)
  - Battle, George Gordon (Box 1)
  - Bellows, Henry Whitney (1814-1882 ) (Box 1)
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson (Mrs. August) (Box 1)
  - Bliss, Cornelius N. (Box 1)
  - Boorman, James (1783-1866) (Box 2)
  - Bowker, Richard Rogers (Box 2)
  - Bruere, Henry (Box 2)
  - Burlingham, Charles Culp (Box 2)
  - Butler Nicholas Murray (Box 2)
  - Byrne, James (Box 2)
  - Cantor, Jacob A. (Box 2)
  - Carnegie, Louise W. (Box 2)
  - Chandler, Charles F. (Box 2)
  - Coler, Bird S. (Box 2)
  - Comstock, Ada (Box 2)
  - Cook, Russel S. (1811-1864) (Box 2)
  - Cortelyou, George B. (Box 2)
  - Cravath, Paul D. (Box 2)
  - Crofton, Edward Henry Churchill, 3rd Baron Crofton (1834-1912 ) (Box 2)
  - Cutting, R. Bayard (Box 3)
  - Cutting, R. Fulton (Box 3)
  - Damrosch, Robert (Heino) (Box 3)
  - de Forest, Robert Weeks 192 0 (Box 3)
  - de Forest, Robert Weeks, 1920-end-Dz (Box 4)
  - Dell, Floyd (Box 4)
  - Devine, Edward T. (Box 4)
  - DeVinne, Theodore Low (Box 4)
  - DeVinne, Theodore Low & Co. (Box 4)
  - Dodge, Cleveland H. (Box 4)
  - Dodge, Grace H. (Box 4)
  - Dodge, Marcellus Hartley (Box 4)
  - Dreier, Mary E. (Box 4)
  - Eliot, Charles W. (Box 5)
  - Eliot, Samuel (1821-189 8 (Box 5)
  - Elkus, Abram I. (Box 5)
  - Falkner, Roland P. (Box 5)
  - Fargo, James Congdel (1829-1915 ) (Box 5)
  - Farrand, Livingston (Box 5)
  - Finley, John H. (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 5)
  - Flagler, Harry Harkness (Box 5)
  - Folks, Homer (Box 6)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson (Box 6)
  - France, Joseph Irwin (Box 6)
  - Gerry, Elbridge T. (Box 6)
  - Giddings, Franklin H. (Box 6)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson (Box 6)
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia C. (Box 6)
  - Gilman, William C. (Box 6)
  - Goodnow, Frank Johnson (Box 6)
  - Gould, Elgin Ralston Lovell (Box 6)
  - Green, John Cleve (1800-1875) (Box 6)
  - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 6)
  - Hapgood, Norman (Box 6)
  - Harriman, Florence J. (Box 6)
  - Hartley, Marcellus (Box 6)
  - Hayes, Ralph (Box 6)
  - Heckscher, A. (August) (Box 6)
  - Hewitt, Abram S. (Box 6)
  - Higgins, Frank Wayland (Box 6)
  - Hilles, Charles D. (Box 6)
  - Hine, Lewis W. (Box 6)
  - Holmes, John Haynes (Box 6)
  - Hoover, Herbert C. (Box 6)
  - Hopkins, Harry L. (Box 6)
  - Hyslop, James H. (Box 6)
  - Isaacs, Stanley (Box 6)
  - Jay, Anna (1783-1856) (Box 6)
  - Jay, Eliza Clarkson (Box 6)
  - Jerome, William Travers (Box 6)
  - Kelley, Florence (Box 7)
  - Kellogg, Paul Underwood (Box 7)
  - Kellor, Frances (Box 7)
  - Kittredge, Mabel Hyde (Box 7)
  - Knox, Philander Chase (Box 7)
  - LaFollette, Robert M. (Box 7)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello H. (Box 7)
  - Lasker, Bruno (Box 7)
  - Lathrop, Julia C. (Box 7)
  - Lederle, Ernst J. (Box 7)
  - Lee C.(Charles) A.(Alfred) (1801-1872) (Box 7)
  - Leffingwell, Russell C. (Box 7)
  - Lehman, Herbert H. (Box 7)
  - Lenox, J.(James) (1800-1880) (Box 7)
  - Lenroot, Katharine F. (Box 7)
  - Lindsay, Samuel McCune (Box 7)
  - Lovejoy, Owen R. (Box 7)
  - Lowell, Josephine Shaw (copy on Microfilm MNA) (Box 8)
  - Luce, Henry R. (Box 8)
  - McAneny, George (Box 8)
  - McClellan, George B. (1865-1940) (Box 8)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble (Box 8)
  - Macy, Valentine Everit (Box 8)
  - Marks, Marcus M. (Box 8)
  - Mason, Alfred Bishop (Box 8)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 8)
  - Merrill, Charles E. Jr. (Box 8)
  - Mills, Ogden L. (Box 8)
  - Minturn, Robert Bowne (1805-1866) (Box 8)
  - Mitchel, John Purroy (Box 8)
  - Morgenthau, Henry (Box 8)
  - Morrow, Dwight W. (Box 8)
  - Moses, Robert (Box 8)
  - Muhlenberg, William Augustus (1796-1877) (Box 8)
  - Murrow, Edward R. (Box 8)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 8)
  - O'Brien, John P. (1873-1951) (Box 8)
  - Odell, Benjamin B. (Box 8)
  - O'Dwyer, William (Box 8)
  - Ogden, David B. (Box 8)
  - Paine, Robert Treat (Box 8)
  - Parker, Willard (Box 8)
  - Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews (Box 8)
  - Parsons, Herbert (Box 8)
  - Parsons, William Barclay (Box 8)
  - Peabody, George Foster (Box 8)
  - Pellew, Henry E. (Box 8)
  - Pendleton, Ellen F. (Box 8)
  - Penrose, Boies (Box 8)
  - Perkins, Frances (Box 9)
  - Perkins, George W. (Box 9)
  - Phelps, Charles Henry (Box 9)
  - Potter H. (Henry) C.(Codman) (Box 9)
  - Prentice, Sartell (Box 9)
  - Purdy, Lawson (Box 9)
  - Putman, George Haven (Box 9)
  - Reid, D.(David) B.(Boswell) (1850-1863 ) (Box 9)
  - Rice, Henry (Box 9)
  - Riis, Jacob A. (Box 9)
  - Riis, Mary (Mrs. Jacob A.) (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich (Mrs. John D., Jr.) (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Ill (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box 9)
  - Rockefeller, Winthrop (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Edith K. (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor R. (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Kermit (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Jr. (Box 9)
  - Root, Elihu (Box 9)
  - Rose, Chauncey (1794-1877 ) (Box 9)
  - Rosenman, Samuel I. (Box 9)
  - Rowe, Leo S. (Box 9)
  - Ruml, Beardsley (Box 9)
  - Schieffelin, William Jay (Box 10)
  - Schiff, Jacob H. (Box 10)
  - Schiff, Mortimer L. (Box 10)
  - Schurz, Carl L. (Box 10)
  - Seligman, DeWitt J. (Box 10)
  - Seligman, Issac N. (Box 10)
  - Sloan, Alfred P., Jr. (Box 10)
  - Smith, Alfred E. (Box 10)
  - Spellman, Francis Cardinal (Box 10)
  - Speyer, James (Box 10)
  - Stelzle, Charles (Box 10)
  - Stevens, Wallace (Box 10)
  - Stimson, Henry L. (Box 10)
  - Stokes, Helen Lousia Phelps (Mrs. Anson Phelps Stokes) (Box 10)
  - Stokes, Isaac Newton Phelps (Box 10)
  - Tarbell, Ida Minerva (Box 10)
  - Thomas, Norman Matoon (Box 10)
  - Throop, Montgomery H. (Box 10)
  - Van Rensselaer, M.(Marianna) G.(Griswold) (Box 10)
  - Veiller, Lawrence (1898-1922 ) (Box 10)
  - Veiller, Lawrence (1922-on ) (Box 11)
  - Verplanck, Gulian Crommelin (1786-1870 ) (Box 11)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison (Box 11)
  - Wagner, Robert F. (Box 11)
  - Wald, Lillian D. (Box 11)
  - Warburg, Felix M. (Box 11)
  - Warburg, Paul M. (Box 11)
  - Watson, Thomas J. (Box 11)
  - Westerfield, Joseph (Box 12)
  - Whalen, Grover A. (Box 12)
  - White, Alfred T. (Box 12)
  - Wickersham, George W. (Box 12)
  - Williams, Talcott (Box 12)
  - Wise, Stephen S. Wood ( (Box 12)
  - Wood, Fernando (1812-1881 ) (Box 12)
  - Wood, Leonard (Box 12)
  - Woolley, Mary E. (Box 12)
- Series II: Catalogued Manuscripts And Documents
  - Churchill, Winston Leonard Spencer (Box 12)
  - Devine, Edward T. (Box 12)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson (Box 12)
  - Higgins, Frank Wayland (Box 12)
  - Hopkins, Harry L. (Box 12)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (Box 12)
  - Kelley, Florence (Box 12)
  - Lowell, Josephine Shaw (Box 12)
  - Odell, Benjamin B. (Box 12)
  - Purdy, Lawson (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 12)
  - Walker, James J. (Box 12)
- Series III: Catalogued Photographs
  - Beaks, Alfred Tennyson (Box 12)
  - Beals, Jessie TarBox (A-L ) (Box 12)
  - Beals, Jessie TarBox (M-Z continued) (Box 13)
  - Churchill, A.E. (Box 13)
  - Hine, Lewis W. (Box 13)
  - Hudson, Holland (Box 13)
  - Myers, Hiram (Box 13)
  - Riis, Jacob A. (Box 13)
- Series IV: Association For Improving The Condition Of The Poor
  - Subseries IV.1: Classified Files
    Files have been left in original AICP numerical classification. See: "Historical Data Index", Appendix I. See also: Bound Volumes
    - Monthly Reports of Visitors (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The How, What and Why of AICP Services (Budget Report, 1936) (Box 14, Folder 1.1)
    - Annual Meeting - General Correspondence, 1912-1935 (Box 14, Folder 1.6)
    - By-Laws, 1913-1933 (Box 14, Folder 1.7)
    - Junior Sea Breeze, 1906-1912 (Box 14, Folder 2.1)
    - Bailey B. Burritt (Biographies, Speeches 1924-1939 etc.) (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Caroline Rest, 1907-1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Joint Application Bureau, 1888-1912 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Joint Application Bureau, 1924-1933 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Lodging Houses, 1907-1917 (including photographs) (Box 15, Folder 5.1)
    - Farm Colony (Sea View Farms) 1909-1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Unemployment Problems, 1908-1929, 1930-1933 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Unemployment Problems, February - November 1930 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Unemployment Problems June 1930 - December 1933 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Special Committee on permanent aspects of unemployment, 1930-1931 (Box 16, Folder 7.4)
    - TERA (Harry Hopkins) (Box 16, Folder 7.9)
    - Sea Breeze Hospital, General Correspondence, 1905-1915 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Sea Beach Hospital, 1906-1915 (Box 16, Folder 12.2)
    - Sea Side Park, 1904-1915 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - New York Tuberculosis Association, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 14.18)
    - Mothers' Allowances, 1925-1928 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Legislation - Widows' Pensions, Board of Child Welfare, 1914-1932 (Box 17, Folder 15.7)
    - Widows' Pension Legislation, 1910-1915 (Box 17, Folder 15.7)
    - Legislation - NYC Department of Public Welfare, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 15.19)
    - Old Age Security Bill, 1928-1931 (Box 18, Folder 15.20)
    - Domestic Relations Court Legislation, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 15.23)
    - Committee for Security Legislation; Unemployment Insurance, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 15.24)
    - Milk, 1905-1920 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - New York Milk Committee, 1908-1926 (with photos) (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - New York Congestion Committee, 1907-1915 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Fund Raising, 1922-1938 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Fund Raising (Box 19, Folder 26.1)
    - Relief Bureau, 1905-1936 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Dependency - Report on a study of 64 cases, by Mary M. Sturges, 1916 (Box 19, Folder 37.4)
    - McLean's study of Relief Department 1912 (Box 20, Folder 37.8)
    - Relief Bureau Reports - Case Summaries and Memoranda, 1925-1937 (Box 20, Folder 37.8)
    - Relief Bureau Reports - Statistical, 1929-1937 (Box 20, Folder 37.8)
    - Widows' Pensions, ca. 1913-1920 (Box 20, Folder 37.10)
    - Desertion Bureau Reports, 1914-1935 (Box 21, Folder 37.12)
    - Bronx Local Office Relief, 1916-1927 (Box 21, Folder 37.13)
    - Transportation Agreements, 1916-1927 (Box 21, Folder 37.16)
    - 23rd Street Workroom, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - A Men's Toy Shop; Sewing Bureau Workroom; Crawford Shops (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Milbank Public Baths, 1905-1925 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - A Milbank Public Baths, 1888-1906 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Institute of Family Relations, 1931-1939 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Admiralty Law (Shop Safety), 1912-1918 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing, 1907-1926 (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing Reports, 1925-1933, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 57.1)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing Minutes, 1915-1925 (Box 22, Folder 57.2)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing Fiscal-year Report, Alta E. Dines, 1925 (Box 22, Folder 57.3)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing, Mental Hygiene (Box 23, Folder 57.4)
    - Bureau of Educational Nursing Report, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 57.5)
    - Visiting Nurse Service, 1928-1938 (Box 23, Folder 57.6)
    - Maternity Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 57.7)
    - Tenement Houses, 1905-1925 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Annual Statistics, 1935-1936 (Box 24, Folder 61.1)
    - Study of Administration (Box 24, Folder 61.1)
    - Annuity Plan; 1911-1931 Employees Medical Exam (Box 24, Folder 61.1a)
    - General Orders, 1991-1931 Manual, 1936 (Box 24, Folder 61.5)
    - Staff Training, 1921-1924 (Box 24, Folder 61.8)
    - Staff Conferences, 1926-1927 (Box 24, Folder 61.9)
    - Protestant Fund, 1934-1936 (Box 25, Folder 61.16)
    - New York City Department of Health, 1921-1939 (Box 25, Folder 62.7)
    - Hospital Social Services in New York City, 1905-1927 (Box 25, Folder 63)
    - Joint Relief Bureau, 1906-1914 (Box 25, Folder 66)
    - Visiting Housekeeper, 1904-1922 (Box 25, Folder 67)
    - Relief Work, 1907-1918 (Box 25, Folder 71)
    - Statistics Bureau Reports, 1928-1937 (Box 26, Folder 75)
    - Statistics and Registration Bureau, 1934-1938 (Box 26, Folder 75.3)
    - Fresh Air Activities (Box 26, Folder 76)
    - Children's School Farm (Box 27, Folder 79)
    - Protestant Charities (Box 27, Folder 79.1)
    - Dependent Children, 1912 (Box 27, Folder 82)
    - Safety (Box 27, Folder 85)
    - Peacock Ball (Box 28, Folder 86a)
    - Committee on Prevention of Tuberculosis (Box 28, Folder 86.4)
    - Jefferson Needlecraft Shop, 1924-1928 (Box 28, Folder 86.4)
    - Houston House Auxiliary (Stuyvesant Clinic) 1924-1933 (Box 28, Folder 86.10)
    - Washington Clinic Auxiliary, 1924-1928 (Box 28, Folder 86.11)
    - Tuberculosis - Family Reports (Box 28, Folder 86.12)
    - Survey of AICP Tuberculosis Work, Wm. T. Dhoerty, 1923-1935 (Box 29, Folder 86.12a)
    - Opportunity Shop - Corporation Matters, 1926-1927 (Box 29, Folder 86.13)
    - Dental Nutrition Reports, 1931-1933 (Box 29, Folder 86.15)
    - Medical Service Club (Box 29, Folder 86.16)
    - Dental Nutrition Reports, 1934-1937 (Box 29, Folder 86.20)
    - Monday Club, 1913-1937 (Box 29, Folder 96)
    - Domestic Relations Court, 1911-1937 (Box 29, Folder 104)
    - Bowling Green Neighborhood Association, 1923-1927 (Box 30, Folder 109)
    - Federated Financing, 1934-1937 (Box 30, Folder 119.2)
    - Social Service Exchange, 1928-1934 (Box 30, Folder 119.9)
    - Survey Associates, 1919-1938 (Box 30, Folder 121)
    - American Red Cross, 1913-1924 (Box 31, Folder 122)
    - American Red Cross Disaster Relief Committees, 1934-1938 (Box 31, Folder 122)
    - East Harlem Health Center, Reports and Pamphlets, 1928-1937 (Box 31, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center, Correspondence, 1931-1937 (Box 31, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1919-1923 (Box 32, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1926-1928 (Box 32, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1929-1930 (Box 32, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center Miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 122.2)
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1922-1929 – Minutes (Box 33, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Health Demonstration, 1934-1938 - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service (Box 33, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing Demonstration, 1928 – Reports (Box 33, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing Demonstration, 1923-1925 - Reports and Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing an d Health Demonstration, 1920, 1928 (Box 34, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Demonstration Minutes and Reports, 1922-1938 (Box 34, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Study (Box 34, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 122.2a)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 35, Folder 122.2a2)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Minutes, Governing Board, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 122.2a3)
    - East Harlem Nursing and Health Service - Kips Bay Day Nursery Property (Box 35, Folder 122. 2a5)
    - East Harlem Nursing Demonstration - various reports and sketches (Box 35, Folder 122. 2b)
    - Community Committee, 1907-1926 (Box 35, Folder 125)
    - AICP Personnel (Box 35, Folder 126)
    - AICP Credit Bureau, 1921 (Box 35, Folder 126.1)
    - Pension Plan (Box 35, Folder 126.2)
    - Columbus Hill (Box 36, Folder 132)
    - Clinton Neighborhood Dispensary, 1928-1939 (Box 36, Folder 132.2)
    - Volunteers (Box 36, Folder 141)
    - Albert Milbank; Percy R. Pyne (Box 36, Folder 163)
    - Harlem Tuberculosis Study (Box 36, Folder 168)
    - W.H. Matthews (Box 36, Folder 175)
    - R. Fulton Cutting Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 177)
    - C.C. Burlingham, 1907-1934 182 Cornelius N. Bliss, 1907-1931 (Box 37, Folder 180)
    - Cornelius N. Bliss, 1931-1934 (Box 37, Folder 182)
    - George Blagden (Box 37, Folder 183)
    - Crippled Children, 1907-1924 (Box 37, Folder 197)
    - Public Baths, 1891-1913 (Box 37, Folder 218)
    - John A. Kingsbury, 1910-1938 (Box 38, Folder 220)
    - Bronx Division, 1931-1938 (Box 38, Folder 222)
    - Bronx District Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 222)
    - Bronx Committee, 1915-1917 (Box 38, Folder 222.2)
    - Bronx District Reports, 1929-1938 (Box 38, Folder 222.5)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1933-1939 (Box 39, Folder 225)
    - Budget Conferences, 1906-1910 (Box 39, Folder 226)
    - Committee on Neighborhood Health Development, 1935, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 227)
    - Committee on Neighborhood Health Department Reports, 1937-1939 (Box 39, Folder 227)
    - Neighborhood Health Development - Mott Haven District (Box 39, Folder 227)
    - Neighborhood Health Development - Yorkville District (Box 39, Folder 227)
    - District Committee Organization, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 227a)
    - Health Services for the School Child, 1936-1940 (Box 40, Folder 227b)
    - Neighborhood Health Development, Technical Advisory Committee, Minutes 1936-1939 (Box 40, Folder 227c)
    - Neighborhood Health Development - Reports of activities of District Health Committees (Box 40, Folder 227.4)
    - Neighborhood Health Development - Milbank Support (Box 40, Folder 227.4)
    - Edward T. Devine Correspondence (Box 40, Folder 230)
    - Charity Organization Society et al., 1894-1928 (Box 40, Folder 231)
    - Joint Council of Welfare Societies (Box 41, Folder 231)
    - Judson Health Center (Box 41, Folder 231.1)
    - Judson Health Center, 1923-1939 (Box 41, Folder 231.1)
    - Committee on Health, New York Principals Association (Box 41, Folder 232)
    - Milbank Appropriations (Box 41, Folder 232.2)
    - Letters to Mayor LaGuardia, 1934-1938 (Box 41, Folder 235)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 41, Folder 265)
    - Executive Committee of Planning Committee, 1929-1930 (Box 42, Folder 265.1)
    - Executive Committee of Planning Committee, 1930-1931 (Box 42, Folder 265.1)
    - White House Conference - Child Health, 1930 (Box 42, Folder 265.la)
    - White House Conference - Child Health, 1931 (Box 42, Folder 265.1a)
    - Sunset Lodge (Box 42, Folder 269.1)
    - New Boys' Campsite at Interstate Park (Box 42, Folder 269. 5b)
    - Overhill Cottage, 1928-1930 (Box 43, Folder 269.8)
    - Open Stair Tenements, 1911-1922 (Box 43, Folder 271)
    - Feeble-minded (Box 43, Folder 271.1)
    - Feeble-minded, 1911-1912 (Box 43, Folder 274.8)
    - Feeble-minded, 1914 (Box 43, Folder 274.8)
    - Feeble-minded Institutions (sic), 1914 (Box 43, Folder 274.9)
    - Factory Investigation Commission, 1912-1914 (Box 43, Folder 278)
    - Church and Social Work, 1919-1927 (Box 44, Folder 282)
    - Board of Inebriety - Superintendency, 1913-1947 (Box 44, Folder 286.1)
    - Boar of Inebriety, 1916-1917 (Box 44, Folder 286.2)